





ABOUT ME

Software Engineering Contractor at Indeed, Computer Information Systems undergraduate at UFMG.

Passionate about being a part of relevant solutions.

I'm a Full-stack Software Engineer with a little over three years of experience. Through this time, I've had the opportunity to work with several different languages, frameworks and technological tools. If one of them is listed here, it means I've had at least a few experiences with solving reasonably complex real-world problems with it.

EXPERIENCE

10/2022 - ongoing **Software Engineer** Contract, Full time

Indeed

Development and maintenance of software solutions for Indeed's job seeker platform. Work conducted concerns web accessibility; library and technology migrations; code refactoring; test suite improvement (both unit and integration tests on a CI/CD environment).

React / TypeScript / Spring Boot / Java / CI/CD / GitLab Pipelines

2/2022 - 10/2022 Software Engineer Internship

Cobli

Design and development of software solutions in a large microservice ecosystem. Work done contemplates active participation in team discussions such as design proposals, SCRUM ceremonies and technical issues, conceptual software architecture and engineering, applying of principles of Domain-driven Design and Event-driven Architecture and, finally, development of software using TypeScript, React, Kotlin, Springboot and GraphQL.

React / TypeScript / Spring Boot / Kotlin

Part time

4/2020 - 09/2023 Machine Learning / Data Science Research Assistant

DCC/UFMG

Participation in two different research projects from the Computer Science Department at Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais: one in Social Network data gathering, processing and analysis related to the development of the COVID-19 pandemic; the other in Natural Language Processing, helping the state of Minas Gerais' government institutions classify and organize large amounts of unstructured data.

Python / Pandas / Machine Learning / Data Science

3/2021 - 2/2022 Part time

Full-stack Developer

ReVirtua

React, PHP and Wordpress web development as a service for medium to large sized companies. Automated chart building and integration with Google Workspace and Google Apps Script (GAS) for control of internal data. Work done contemplates API building and consuming, GAS, Type-Script, JavaScript and PHP software development and the building of two chatbot services with TypeScript, Express and IBM Watson

React / TypeScript / Node.js / Express

6/2020 - 9/2021

Frontend Developer

iJunior

Junior enterprise collaborative work as a Web Developer, providing web solutions for small to medium sized companies. Work done contemplates full-stack software development with JavaScript and Python, using the React, Express and Flask frameworks.

React / JavaScript / Node.js / Express / Flask / Python

PUBLICATIONS

2022 - Article

COVID-19 on Twitter: correlating vocabulary with the agravatation and attenuation of the pandemic in Brazil 🗹

Proceedings of the 11th Brazilian Workshop on Social Network Analysis and Mining

2022 - Paper

Correlations between Web Searches and COVID-19 Epidemiological Indicators in Brazil 🗗 **Brazilian Archives of Biology and Technology**

EDUCATION

2020 - Ongoing CIS Bachelor's Degree

Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais

Computer Information Systems undergraduate, ¾ through the program.

TECHNOLOGIES

 $\begin{array}{lll} \textbf{React} & 3 \text{ years of experience} \\ \textbf{Node.js} & 2 \text{ years of experience} \\ \textbf{Python} & 2 \text{ years of experience} \\ \textbf{JavaScript} & 3 \text{ years of experience} \\ \textbf{TypeScript} & 2 \text{ years of experience} \\ \textbf{Java} & 1\frac{1}{2} \text{ years of experience} \\ \end{array}$

KNOWLEDGE

Agile Methodologies OOP Principles Documentation Practices Domain-Driven Development Event-Driven Architecture

LANGUAGES

English - Proficient TOEFL 114/120 **Portuguese** - Native